Alessandro Roic



Front end developer with 2 years of experience building modular and responsive website design. Capable of managing projects independently, able to plan and organize my work in a systematic way. Focused on details, on keeping up with deadlines and pre-established budgets. Always eager to improve my skills with hands-on experience and interested in learning new technologies.

Experience

➡ FEBRUARY 2021 - CURRENTLY

Front End Developer / Accenture, Rome, Italy

- Designed and developed autonomously a web application for data visualization (Nexi)
- Optimized and improved a ui-kit embedded in a service platform (Italian Ministry of Economy)
- Build services and components for a customer service platform (Poste Italiane)
- Collaborated in a Scrum team, following closely and participated actively in daily activities with the engineers, designers and clients.

CTOBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2021

Full-Stack Developer / Jpanik , Rome, Italy

- Developed Back End services with Spring framework suite and Front End components with Angular, for a web enterprise platform designed for clinical-hospital management
- Integrated an applet into the platform that processes and displays an interactive graph using the elaborated data using the Chart.js library.

Education

☐ SEPTEMBER 2016 - APRIL 2020

Bachelor of Computer Science / Sapienza University of Rome

☐ SEPTEMBER 2017 - MARCH 2018

Study Abroad / Rijksuniversiteit Groningen, Netherlands

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS/Sass, Javascript (ES6+), Typescript
- Libraries & Frameworks: Angular, NgRx, Node.js, Bootstrap, RxJs, Redux, Chart.js
- Tools & Platforms: Git, Jira, Gitlab

Languages

- English: professional proficiency IELTS 7.5 (C1)
- Italian: mother tongue

Projects

- Personal Website: developed in Angular 11, NgRx and Bootstrap through Github pages
- **E-Quality:** gamified video game built for kids to raise awareness on gender equality in collaboration with the Italian Regional Councilor for Equal Opportunities
- Curiosone Bot: interactive chatbot written in Java
- AirborneAssault: video game build with libGDX for the university Java course